

# Taeyoung Kim

AUTONOMOUS DRIVING · ROBOTICS SW ENGINEER

340, Mokdongseo-ro, Yangcheon-gu, Seoul, 08089, Republic of Korea

 $\square \ (+82) \ 10-9686-8177 \ | \ \blacksquare \ tyoung96@naver.com \ | \ \ \mbox{\em $\alpha$ taeyoung96.github.io} \ | \ \ \mbox{\em $\Omega$} \ Taeyoung96$ 

"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."

# **Summary**.

This is Taeyoung Kim, who wants to become an autonomous driving or robotics SW engineer. My research interests are Computer Vision and Sensor Fusion. I like to take on challenging tasks and I like to grow up with my colleagues around me. That's why I record and share what I did on my Github or Technical Blog. I would like to participate in changing the world with advanced science and technology.

## Research Interests

**Computer Vision** Object Detection, Segmentation, Depth Estimation

**Sensor Fusion** Combination of camera, lidar, and radar

# **Education**

**Kwang Woon University** 

Seoul, S.Korea

B.S. IN SCHOOL OF ROBOTICS

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2022 (Expected)

- Current GPA: 4.07 / 4.50, Current Major GPA: 4.50 / 4.50
- Club: BARAM (Robotics Academic Group) [2020 Staff] , DAISY (English Conversation Club) [2019 Spring President]

# Work Experience\_

## KIST(Korea Institute of Science and Technology)

Seoul, S.Korea

STUDENT INTERN (ADVISOR: DR. KANGGEON KIM)

Sep. 2020 - Present

- Research on Monocular Depth Estimation
- Participated in KIST disinfect robot (Al Disinfection Robot) project

#### Image Process System Lab @Kwang Woon Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

Mar. 2020 - Aug. 2020

Undergraduate Lab Intern (Advisor : Prof. Donggyu Sim)

• Research on Image Processing based on Deep learning

Participated in seminars related to Deep Learning and Image Processing

# **Honors & Awards**

#### **AWARDS**

2020.11 **Dean's List,** for Academic Excellence KwangWoon Univ.

2020.9 **5th Place on B-track**, Korea Health Datathon 2020 

\*\*PLATFORM\*\*

\*\*PLATFORM\*\*

2019.10 **Dean's List**, for Academic Excellence KwangWoon Univ.

#### Honors

National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship , Korea Student Aid
for the students with excellent grades, those who have been recommended by the university Foundation

2019-2 **Full tuition Scholarship**, for Top seat last semester *KwangWoon Univ.* 

## Skills

**Programming** C++/C, Python, JAVA, Matlab **Framework** Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras

**DevOps** Git, Docker, ROS **Languages** Korean, English

DECEMBER 10, 2020 TAEYOUNG KIM · CURRICULUM VITAE 1

# **Extracurricular Activity**

**Technical Blogs**Github blog

• Writing some posts about lecture summary, paper review, some tips for developments.

To share what I have studied with others and to remember it longer.

#### **Monocular Depth Estimation with ORB-SLAM2**

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT

WRITERS

Sep. 2020 - Nov. 2020

May. 2020 - Present

Aug. 2020

- I was curious about the performance of the recent depth estimation model.
- I used 'Monocular Depth Estimation with Transfer Learning pretrained MobileNetV2' model and applied to ORB-SLAM2 also compared with ORB-SLAM2(Monocular mode), ORB-SLAM2(RGB-D mode)
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

KCCV 2020 Korea computer vision society

PARTICIPANT

Participated to know about the trend of Computer Vision

Using deep learning for data analysis and image processing (Basic)

Korea open source software

STUDENTS

• Studied lectures which is related to the using Deep learning framework(Keras)

**Runner Alarm System based on Deep Learning** 

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

Personal Toy Project Apr. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- · I wanted to distinguish between walking children and running children with an object detection model.
- When children are running for an amount of time, a beep sounds.
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

## **Publication**

### DOMESTIC CONFERENCE

**KSPC2020**, Naseong Kwon, Taeyoung Kim, Subin Kim, Joohyung Byeon, Jongsuk Lee, Donggyu Sim, "Luma Mapping with Chroma Scaling based on CNN feature map for VVC subjective quality improvement"

IEIE